(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T16:36:09.889540",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あれやこれやと言いますが
Though I may say all sorts of things,
どうか探してみてみせて
please go on and try to find me.
嘘と本音の間 上手に隠しといたんで
I skillfully hid between lies and true feelings.
ストリーミングハート
Streaming Heart
一人じゃダメなんだと押して 二人になればハッピー
Useless when alone, but together we're happy.
そのうち二人が嫌で 一人がいいとか言って
Soon we'll hate each other, saying "I want to be alone."
固定のしようもない感情の 行き着く先はどこでしょう
Where do these unfixable emotions go?
溺れそうになった代償に また酸素を見つけちゃうんだ
Drowning in need, I seek out air once more.
弱虫だね 堕ちることが 心地良くてさ
Being a coward who falls feels so good.
アイマイにしたいのさ 好きでいてって歪んでく内省
I want to love you, but my inner voice is warped.
アイマイにしたいのさ 嫌いになってしまえたら大成功
I want to love you, and if you hate me, that's a success.
一人じゃダメなんだと押して 二人になればハッピー
Useless when alone, but together we're happy.
そのうち二人が嫌で 一人がいいとか言って
Soon we'll hate each other, saying "I want to be alone."
どうせなら僕がもう一人 いるならそれはそれでハッピーだ
If I have another "me," then that's happy too.
今日は僕が女の子 演じ合ってバカみたいにさ
Today I play the girl, acting silly like a fool.
エゴママだと知りながらも ヤメラレナイのさ
Even knowing it's egotistical, I can't stop.
アイマイにしたいのさ 好きでいてって歪んでく内省
I want to love you, but my inner voice is warped.
アイマイにしたいのさ 嫌いになってしまえたら大成功
I want to love you, and if you hate me, that's a success.
一人じゃダメなんだと押して 二人になればハッピー
Useless when alone, but together we're happy.
そのうち二人が嫌で 一人がいいとか言って
Soon we'll hate each other, saying "I want to be alone."
どうせなら僕がもう一人 だならそれはそれでハッピーだ
If I'm just by myself, then that's happy too.
今日も僕が女の子 返し合ってパペットみたいにさ
Today I'm a girl, replying back and forth like a doll.
バイバイをしたいのさ 僕でいてって楽しくないんだ
I want to say goodbye, even if being me isn't fun.
大雑把にしたいのさ もう…もう…もう…
I want to make it rough, more and more, more...
あれやこれやと言いましたが
Though I may say all sorts of things,
どうか探してみてみせて
please go on and try to find me.
嘘と本音の間 上手に隠しといたんで
I skillfully hid between lies and true feelings.
あれやこれや言いますが どうか探してみて
Though the things I say might not make sense,
ウソと本音の間 上手く隠しといたんで
In the space between truth and lies, I hid it well.
一人じゃダメな同士で 二人になればハッピー
Useless alone, but together as two, we're happy.
そのうち二人飽きて 「一人がいい」とか言って
Soon we tire of each other and say 'I'd rather be alone'.
固定のしようもない感情の 行き着く先はどこでしょう
Where do these unfixable emotions lead us?
溺れそうになった代償に また酸素を見つけちゃうんだ
In exchange for almost drowning, I find oxygen again.
弱虫だね 落ちることが
Such a coward, falling
心地良くてさ
feels so comfortable.
アイマイにしたいのさ
I want to keep it vague.
好きでいてって 歪んでく内声
Begging 'please love me' with a distorted voice,
アイマイにしたいのさ
I want to keep it vague.
嫌いになってしまえたら 大成功
If you end up hating me, that's a huge success.
一人じゃダメな同士で 二人になればハッピー
Useless alone, but together as two, we're happy.
そのうち二人飽きて 「一人がいい」とか言って
Soon we tire of each other and say 'I'd rather be alone'.
どうせなら僕がもう一人 いるならそれはそれでハッピーだ
If there's already another me, then that's happy too.
今日が僕が女の子 演じ合ってバカみたいにさ
Playing girls today, acting like fools.
エゴママだ知っていながらも やめられないのさ
Knowing it's egomama, I still can't stop.
アイマイにしたいのさ
I want to keep it vague.
好きでいてって 歪んでく内声
Begging 'please love me' with a distorted voice.
にっこにっこに～
Nikkonikko ni~
「アア、マイクOK！いくよー！」
"Ah, mic OK! Here we go!"
ミニスカートで襲撃だ！（キュン）
Ambush in a miniskirt! (Kyun)
ギャップ萌えして衝撃だ！（キュン）
Shocked by gap moe! (Kyun)
恋の妄想 回路暴走 デマ デマ ホラ
Love delusions, circuit overload, false, false, rumors!
「だ、だ、だ、だ、大好き」告ってちょうだいよ
Saying "I-I-I-I love you!"
だっちゅーけどうクールにルーズビート聞かせて バリバリチューン
Let's hear the loose and cool beat, bari-bari tune!
ビバハピ
Viva Happy
切なくて もやるせなくても
Even when feeling painful or frustrated,
（カバディ×6）Fight！「もうっ！」
(Kabaddi x6) Fight! "Geez!"
あの娘になんて なれないから
Since I can never be like that girl,
（カバディ×6）Fight！
(Kabaddi x6) Fight!
ありのままの自分を 愛せれば que sera, sera
Love your true self, que sera, sera.
今はひとりぼっちの 君に歌をあげる 「はい、どうぞ」
Now I'll give a song to you, who's all alone. "Here you go!"
ビビ ビビビ
Vi- vi- vi-vi-vi
ビバ！ ビバ！ ハッピー (chu-lu-chu-chu)
Viva! Viva Happy! (chu-lu-chu-chu)
イアイア 争いはしない主義 no-no-non-non
Yeah-yeah, I'm against quarreling, no-no-non-non.
ビバ！ ビバ！ ハッピー (chu-lu-chu-chu)
Viva! Viva Happy! (chu-lu-chu-chu)
ポロポロ涙して 一夜一夜に独り言
Shedding tears drop by drop, talking to myself every single night.
(M・I・K・U)
(M-I-K-U)
叱られても せかされても
Even if I'm scolded or rushed,
（カバディ×6）「うわぁっ！」
(Kabaddi x6) "Whoa!"
ダッシュで結果 求め過ぎよ
You're demanding results too fast with a dash,
（カバディ×6）Fight！
(Kabaddi x6) Fight!
“常識”は いつまでも 大人達のスラング
"Common sense" is forever the slang of adults.
無意識の 宇宙から 君に届くサイン 「はいっ！」
A sign reaching you from the unconscious universe, "Yes!"
ビビ ビビビ
Vi- vi- vi-vi-vi
ビバ！ ビバ！ ハッピー (chu-lu-chu-chu)
Viva! Viva Happy! (chu-lu-chu-chu)
クタクタ睡眠は 8時間 イェ・イェ・イェイ・イェイ
Sleeping exhaustively for 8 hours, yeah-yeah-yeah-yeah!
ビバ！ ビバ！ ハッピー (chu-lu-chu-chu)
Viva! Viva Happy! (chu-lu-chu-chu)
あれこれ したい だけど 「したい！」
I want to do this and that, but "I want to!"
i, my, me, mine キリキリ舞い
I, my, me, mine, running around in circles.
「ハッピーに振る舞う 君が 好きだよ」
"I like you when you act happy."
ちょっと 情情なピーポー チャンス到来も撃沈
A bit of an emotional person, chance arrival ended in defeat.
中途半端なお説教 キタ 「そんなに 世間 は 甘く ない！だから」
Half-baked lecturing arrives: "The world isn't that sweet! That's why..."
「やめてっ！」
"Stop it!"
スルー で アバター に チェンジ！
Switch to an avatar by passing through!
バーチャル・ビーナス ブースト bass で born 「にゃんっ！」
Virtual Venus, boost bass and born, "Meow!"
ビバビビビバビビビビ！ハッピー
Viva-vivi-viva-vivibibi! Happy!
イアイア 争いはしない主義 no-no-non-non
Yeah-yeah, I'm against quarreling, no-no-non-non.
ビバ！ ビバ！ ハッピー (chu-lu-chu-chu)
Viva! Viva Happy! (chu-lu-chu-chu)
ポロポロ涙して 「そんなに 世間 は 甘く ない！」
Shedding tears drop by drop, "The world isn't that sweet!"
ビバ！
Viva!
ハッピーに振る舞う 貴様らが
You bastards acting happy,
言うわけねぇだろ！
As if you'd say that!
ちょっと順情なビート ステップダンス トラウマもキッチリ
A slightly innocent beat, step dance, trauma nicely too.
中途半端なオトナ主張キタ そんなに世間は甘くないだから
Half-baked adult assertions arrive, the world isn't that sweet, so
打つ手無しかよ 擦るぜガポにチェーン
Out of moves, rubbing to gaponi chain
パズルみナスプーストベストでボーン
Puzzle mina boost best and born
にゃんっ！ビバ！ ビバ！ ハッピー (chu-lu-chu-chu)
Meow! Viva! Viva Happy! (chu-lu-chu-chu)
ビバ！ ビバ！ ハッピー (chu-lu-chu-chu)
Viva! Viva Happy! (chu-lu-chu-chu)
イアイア 争いはしない主義 no-no-non-non
Yeah-yeah, I'm against quarreling, no-no-non-non.
ビバ！ ビバ！ ハッピー (chu-lu-chu-chu)
Viva! Viva Happy! (chu-lu-chu-chu)
クタクタ睡眠は 8時間 イェ・イェ・イェイ・イェイ
Sleeping exhaustively for 8 hours, yeah-yeah-yeah-yeah!
ビバ！ ビバ！ ハッピー (chu-lu-chu-chu)
Viva! Viva Happy! (chu-lu-chu-chu)
あれこれ したい だけど 「したい！」 ビバーン！
I want to do this and that, but "I want to!" Vivaaan!
HOLOKOMICS ホロコミックス
[Title: HOLO COMICS]
吾輩の秘密の恋のLOVE はやく俺に愛に恋よ、お前☆
[Lyrics: My Secret Love is You, Hey的前輩~]
秘密だぜ☆ ラプラス・ダークネス。
[Secret, you see☆ Laplus Darknesss]
私の名前はラプラス……
My name is Laplus...
ハイエスト・デサーティン・ダイナアート……
Highest Desartin Dyna Art of Impact...
今日は待ちに待った新学期！！
Today is the long-awaited new semester!!
大好きな俺くんと同じクラスになれるかな！？
Will I be in the same class as my beloved Ore-kun!?
お、俺くん……なんでなの……まさか、こんなコトに……
O-Ore-kun... why... how could this happen...
ラプ！ あんた呼ばれてるよ！！
Lapu! You're being called!!
だれよこんなときに……ぐすっ……
Who could it be at a time like this... *sniff*...
僕だよ。
It's me.
ええっ！？ お、俺くん！？
Eh!? O-Ore-kun!?
我輩に何か用ですか……？
Do you have business with me...?
ラプちゃん、ちょっとこっちに。
Lap-chan, come over here for a sec.
ラプちゃん……秘密を守れるかな？
Lap-chan... can you keep a secret?
はいっ！ もちろんです！
Yes! Of course!
命をかけれるのか……？
Can you stake your life on it...?
い、命だと……？
M-My life...?
何っ、この気持ち……
What is this feeling...?
おいどうなんだよ ねえっ！！何なのっ！！誰か教えてよ！！
Hey, what is this?! Hey! What is it?! Somebody tell me!!
だいしきゅーだいしゅき
Daishikyuu Daishuki ♡
わっちゅー げっちゅー 熱烈おうんちゅー
Whatcha getcha passionate ounchuu
しゅきしゅぎて弾けた vivid マインド
A vivid mind bursting with too much love
ルーレット グッド スタート
Roulette, good start
きっと ゲット
surely get it
1 等！1 等！1 等！
1st place! 1st place! 1st place!
永久センセーキュー ときめき knock you
Eternal top grade, a heart-throbbing knock you
1 ミリの隙間に ダイビング
Diving into a 1-millimeter gap
ラブスタンプ 全部 コンプ 運勢 アップ
Love stamps all comped, fortune up!
いいぞ！いいぞ！いいぞ！いいぞ！
Great! Great! Great! Great!
せーの！
Ready, go!
だって今日はゴッド メンタル
Because today my mental is god-tier
勇ましきチャレンジャー
A valiant challenger
ちょっとだけセンチメンタル
Just a little sentimental
だ・い・し・きゅー・だいしゅき ♡ 123 はいっ！
Da-i-shi-kyuu-daishuki ♡ 123, go!
まみむめもめも目も見れないの
I can't even look you in the eyes
立ちててててと手と手が触れて
As our hands brush against each other
だ・い・し・きゅー・だいしゅきになれ！
Become my absolute favorite!
もっとキュキュッキュッキュート 強制ラブ！
More cute, cute, cute, forced love!
あのねクリオネ 透けてるハート
You know, a clione's translucent heart
でもねこの胸 見透かさないで
But don't see right through my chest
だ・い・し・きゅー・だいしゅきになれ！
Become my absolute favorite!
アタシじゃないなんて終わってんね
Saying it's not me is so over
わっちゅー げっちゅー 熱烈おうんちゅー
Whatcha getcha passionate ounchuu
しゅきしゅぎてからぶるキューティマインド
A cutie mind swinging and missing from too much love
ルーレット ちょっと ストップ
Roulette, little stop
一旦 休憩
Break for a moment
いやっ！
No way!
せーの！
Ready, go!
だって今日は求めてる
Because today I'm searching for
麗しきチャレンジャー
A radiant challenger
ハート描いたオートメーション
An automation drawing hearts
だ・い・し・きゅー・だいしゅき ♡ 123 はいっ！
Da-i-shi-kyuu-daishuki ♡ 123, go!
まみむメロメロメロにしてほしいの
I want you to make me totally head over heels
なにぬ猫猫恋のコネクト
Nani nu, cat cat, connecting in love
だ・い・し・きゅー・だいしゅきになれ！
Become my absolute favorite!
もっとキキキッキュッ強制ラブ！
More ki-ki-ki-q, forced love!
あのねマリオネット 操られレイディ
You know, a marionette, a controlled lady
でもねそれも手は緩くわないで
But even so, don't go easy on me
だ・い・し・きゅー・だいしゅきになれ！
Become my absolute favorite!
アタシじゃないなんて終わってんね
Saying it's not me is so over
フレンドリーなフリして
Putting on a friendly act
周波数を乱さないで
Don't disturb my frequency
惑わす時の魅惑のリップ
The seductive lips at that bewitching moment
リアルになる be love
Becoming real, be love
まみむめもめもめも見れないの
I can't even look you in the eyes
立ちててててと手と手が触れて
As our hands brush against each other
だ・い・し・きゅー・だいしゅきになれ！
Become my absolute favorite!
もっとキュキュキュッと強制ラブ！
More cu-cu-cu, forced love!
あのねクリオネ 透けてるハート
You know, a clione's translucent heart
でもねこの胸 見透かさないで
But don't see right through my chest
だ・い・し・きゅー・だいしゅきになれ！
Become my absolute favorite!
アタシじゃないなんて終わってんね
Saying it's not me is so over
まみむめもめもめ見れないの
Can't even look properly at mami mumemo memo,
立ちすてとてとてと手が触れて
Our hands touch as we stand frozen,
だいしゅーだいしゅーきになれ
Fall deeply, madly in love with me!
もっとぎゅーぎゅーきゅっと狂わせて
Drive me even more crazy, squeeze me tight!
あのねくりよね透けてるハート
You know, my transparent heart is showing,
でもねこの胸に透かさないで
But don't look right through my chest like that!
だいしゅーだいしゅーきになれ
Fall deeply, madly in love with me!
アタシじゃないなんて終わってんね
Saying it's not me is just so over.
みんな…えっと…
Everyone... um...
今日は、一周年ライブに来てくれてありがとうございますっ！
Thank you so much for coming to my 1st anniversary live today!
てかちょっと待って！ちょっとっ！
Wait a second! Hold on!
えっと、ご…この衣装が、みんなに見られるのは初めてだな。
Um, this... this is the first time everyone is seeing this outfit.
イエーイ。
Yay.
で、ホロックスで…えっと、初めて一人目の、お披露目だよ！
And, as Holox's... um, the first person to debut!
トップバッター！常にトップ！常にナンバーワン！
Top batter! Always top! Always number one!
笑うな！笑わないでください！
Don't laugh! Please don't laugh!
じゃ、カメラマンが笑っちゃったので、我が輩が気を取り直してやります。よろしくお願いします！
Well, since the cameraman laughed, I'll pull myself together. Thank you!
で、えっと見て欲しい。後ろにね、大きいリボンがありまして…
And, um, I want you to look. In the back, there's a big ribbon...
我が輩の色のテープ、リボンと、あの謎の、謎のところから出ている尻尾ね。
my colored tape, ribbon, and a tail coming out from some mysterious place.
これ衣装のどこから出したのか自分でも分からないんだけど。
I don't even know where on the outfit I pulled this out from myself.
ちょっと…え、ごめんなさい。あの3曲、3曲続けて踊ったからちょっとすごいことになってる。
Um... ah, I'm sorry. Dancing through three songs in a row made things wild.
えっと、これ、これすごい尻尾が…付いてます。尻尾がついてて
Um, this, this has an amazing tail... attached. A tail is attached!
次、次付けてみて…付けましたからね。うん、デザイン、尻尾のデザインを入れてもらいましたあと、あの風が撮れ、撮れてません。付いてます。
I had the design, the tail design incorporated, and it's attached.
ってこと…足も見て欲しいの。そう、相変わらず、相変わらずね、ここマークが残ってるのと、あと靴下はまた履き忘れティます。たぶん、どこかに忘れてきました。
Yeah, the mark is still here, and I forgot to wear my socks again.
ちょっと、ローアングルやめてください！ちょっと、やめてくださいよ！
Hey, stop with the low angles! Hey, stop it!
そんなつもりねえよみたいな顔をやめろマジで。ってことでね、
Stop making that "I didn't mean that" face, seriously. So anyway,
もうちょっと全身で撮ってもらおうかな。一応ね、見たいでしょ、みんな。
I guess I'll have them take a full-body shot. Everyone wants to see it.
可愛いポーズってあげようかなじゃあ。
Shall I strike a cute pose then?
可愛いポーズとかってめちゃぶりされた！イエーイ！イエーイ！
Being asked on the spot for a cute pose! Yay! Yay!
アイドルっぽいやつだね。アイドルっぽい。
It's an idol-like thing. Idol-like.
ちょっと、恥ずかしい！普通に恥ずかしい！やめて！
Wait, it's embarrassing! Just plain embarrassing! Stop it!
で、ちょっと待って、次、こう靴通すこと忘れました。この、えっと、次にちょっとあの、
Hold on, next, I forgot to put my shoes through. This, um, next...
お披露目するものが、もう一つあります。こっちもね、みんなにはまだ見せたことがないものなのでね、楽しみにして待っていてけたらと思います。
There is one more thing to unveil. I hope you look forward to it.
だから、みんなまだどこにも行かないで！きゃー！
So, everyone, don't go anywhere yet!
じゃ、よろしくお願いします。まだまだ見てね。
Well then, thank you for your support. Keep watching!
はあ…おれくん、こんな時間まで何してるんだろう。
Haah... Ore-kun, what is he doing out until this late?
結婚してもう4年。
It's been already four years since we got married.
我が輩からおれくんへの愛は年々増していっているというのに、
Even though my love for Ore-kun grows stronger every year,
おれくん最近全然構ってくれない。
Ore-kun hasn't been paying attention to me at all lately.
新婚の頃は、お仕事終わったらすぐに帰ってきてくれたのにな。
Back when we were newlyweds, he'd come straight home from work.
今は「終電のがした」とか言って、朝が帰りばっかで。
Now he just says things like "I missed the last train," and comes home in the morning.
我が輩は家にいても暇だから、最近は駅近の24時間やってるカフェで1人寂しくお茶して。
Since I have nothing to do, I've been sipping tea alone in a 24-hour cafe.
おお、珍しい麻雀。
Oh, rare Mahjong.
この時ラプラス・ダークネスは知るよしもなかった。まさかこの後あんなことが起きようとは。いや本当にマジで。
At that time, Laplus had no way of knowing what would happen next. Seriously.
あれ？もう1時間。
Huh? An hour already.
帰ろっかな。
Should I go home?
でもいっか。
Oh well.
もういっしょ。
Once more.
うぇええええ！おれくんが！
Whaaa! Ore-kun is!
おれくんが！女を連れて、今、この店に来店している……！
Ore-kun has brought a woman and is currently visiting this shop...
よ、こ、こいつ何しに、あ、だめだ落ち着け。
H-Hey, what is this guy here for? Ah, no, calm down.
こいつマジで何しに来たんだ？あ、お、女とこんな夜中に
What on earth did this guy come here for? Ah, with a woman at this kind of time of night,
カフェにくそっ！はっ！
at a cafe... Damn it! Ha!
しかも隣の席に座った！こいつ面接してないのかよ！
And they sat right at the next table! Didn't this guy check?
おい！妻が隣に座ってみますけど！
Hey! Your wife is sitting right next to you!
えっ、た、楽しくお話しを始めやがった！誰がこんなん……！
Ah, they started talking happily! Who wanted this...
え、何しようとしている？これは、な、また来てくだいさいね？な、なに！？
Huh, what are they trying to do? Is this... "Please come again"? What?!
こ、これはアフター！？アフターでカフェ？健全だ、ははは！
I-Is this "after work"?! A cafe date after hours? How wholesome, hahaha!
いや、でも他の女といるなんてだめだ！不健全だ！うるせえ！
No, but being with another woman is no good! Unwholesome! Shut up!
なんの話をしている？パンケーキを食べに行く約束をしている？
What are they talking about? Promising to go eat pancakes?
なあ！健全だ！こんな美女とパンケーキ！？
Hey! How wholesome! Pancakes with such a beauty!?
逆に不健全かもしれない！見えない方がえろいてきなやつかもしれない！
Maybe it's unwholesome in reverse! Maybe staying unseen is more erotic!
いや何ね！他の女とパンケーキ食いに行くんだ！何行くんだよ！
No, really! He's going to eat pancakes with another woman! Why are you going?!
何が入ってもパンケーキに行ったことのないのに！なぜだ！許さん！許さん！
Even though I've never been taken to eat pancakes! Why?! I won't forgive you!
デートなんて許さない！おれくん、女友達もぶっ殺す！下がってこい！
I won't allow a date! Ore-kun, I'll kill your female friend too! Get down here!
おい！おい！おめでてえな！おれくん！
Hey! Hey! How celebratory, Ore-kun!
何してんだこんなとこで！
What are you doing in a place like this!
ボクらは毎日、毎日、お家で、おれくんが帰ってくるの、ずっと待ってのに！
We wait at home every single day for Ore-kun to come back!
こんなんで、んで、この女誰だよ！誰だよ！
And yet... Who is this woman?! Who is she?!
ねえ！なんか、なんか言えおい！
Hey! Say something, hey!
ふざけた話して、お前ら許せねえ！ここがお前らの墓場だ！
Talking nonsense, I can't forgive you guys! This is your graveyard!
愛して 愛して 愛して
Love me, love me, love me
はるか遠い遠い昔 巻かれた首輪は
Distantly far away, far away long ago, a coiled necklace
人が欲しい 人が欲しいと叫ぶ呪いの首輪は
"I want people, I want people," it cried, this cursed necklace
怒らないで 見捨てないで どこも行かないで
Don't get angry, don't abandon me, don't go anywhere
強く締める 吐くまで締める 人がいないいないと
It strangles me tightly, till I could throw up, whenever no one's around
いい成績でしょ
Nice grades, huh?
ねぇ ねぇ いい子でしょ
Hey, hey, aren't I a good kid?
かわいい子でしょ
Aren't I a cute kid?
ねぇ ねぇ 良い子でしょう 苦しいね
Hey, hey, I'm good, right? It hurts, hey
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more
愛して 愛して 狂おしい ほど に
Love me, love me, so much that it's maddening
苦しい 離さない 苦しい もっともっと ねぇ
It's painful, I won't let go, more and more, hey
ねえ 馬鹿入って いい子だよ ねぇ
Hey, come on in, aren't I a good kid, hey?
じゃあ もっともっと 愛してくれても
Well then, wouldn't it be nice if you loved me even more?
こっち見て
Look this way
体 体 大きくなっても 小さい首輪は
No matter how big your body grows, this collar remains small
苦しさは足りなくなる 人が人が足りない
It hurts now, it's not enough now, there aren't enough people
クラスの誰にも負けない 綺麗ないい子でしょ
I won't lose to anyone in my class, aren't I a lovely good kid?
あの子より
More than that kid,
もっともっと 誰も彼も 私を見てよ
More and more, everyone, look at me!
体育館裏
Behind the gymnasium...
あなたに告白を 嘘みたいでしょ
A confession to you, seems like a lie, right?
あなたが好きなの 汚いあなたが
I like you, you who are so filthy.
愛して 愛して 愛して 全部あげるあなたに
Love me, love me, love me, I'll give you everything
あなたに
to you...
全部背負ってもらうよ
Have you shoulder everything for me.
当たり前 あなたが
It's only natural, you're...
足りない 話さないよ
Not enough, I won't let you go!
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと愛して
Love me, love me, love me, love me more and more!
愛して 狂おしいほどに
Love me, so maddeningly...
苦しい 話さない
painful, I won't let go,
苦しい もっともっとねぇ
it hurts, more and more, hey...
幸せなの
This is true happiness.
愛して 愛して 愛して
Love me, love me, love me,
もっともっと愛して
love me more and more!
幸せなの
This is true happiness.
はい、ということで
Alright, so...
みんな見て！
everyone, look!
これを見ろ！
Look at this!
ついに、あいつも3Dで...
Finally, even he is in 3D...
抜け出たぞ！
He broke out!
イエーイ、やった！
Yay, we did it!
すごくない？やっとですよ！
Isn't that amazing? It's finally happened!
1周年で、1周年で成し遂げたこと、抜いたこと。
What we accomplished and pulled off in our 1st anniversary.
ああ、このね、ここお気に入りポイントはここです。
Ah, my favorite point here is right here.
我が輩のネクタイは、このベルトの...
My necktie goes through this belt...
ここに通してっていうね。たまに、あの、ファンアートを描いていただいている方で、
Right through here. Sometimes, um, for those of you who draw fan art,
ここどうなってるか分からないみたいな。
you might wonder how this part works.
見ましたっき。3Dで分かると。
Well, now you can see it in 3D.
ここ通ってんだっていうね。下の。いいでしょ？
It goes right through the bottom. Pretty cool, right?
イエーイ！
Yay!
あともう一つある。
Also, there's one more thing.
ここね、穴、ここから尻尾が...
Right here, a hole, the tail comes out from here...
ねえ、むずい！ここから尻尾が出てるんですよ。
Hey, it's tough! The tail comes out from right here.
しょうがなかったでしょ？
Pretty cool, right?
あ、でも我が輩の三面図ね、なめくり回すように見てた人なら分かるかもしれないけどね。今ライト層に向けてアピールしてますから。いいでしょ？イエーイ！
Well, if you've been examining my 3-view reference sheet like crazy, you might know. But I'm appealing to the light fans right now. Pretty cool, right? Yay!
レクスッタがね、履いてない。
My leg-wear isn't... wait, it's not wearing...
あ、そここで、見てください。おー！
Ah, look right there, look at that. Whoa!
いいですか？こんな感じで皆さん、全身がみたい？全身がみたいみたいですね。
How's that? You guys want to see my whole body? Looks like you want to see my whole body.
どうですか？いーや！いーや！いーや！
How's this? Yay! Yay! Yay!
スブーツがね、ここ、ここ見てよ。
These boots, look here, look at this.
我が輩がこう自分の体の見せたのって初めてじゃないですか。こうお披露目とかで大体いつも、はい！みたいな感じで終わるんで、なんか初めてですね。
It's probably the first time I've shown off my body like this. Usually at reveal streams it just ends like, "Ta-da!" So this is a first.
大体なんかこういうお披露目配信にゲストで呼ばれて、あの、一緒に写真撮ったりとかするんだけど、自分の配信で、しかもMCやってないんですよ、我が輩、普段。
Usually I get invited as a guest to reveal streams and take pictures together, but on my own stream, and besides, I don't normally do MC work, you know.
この1周年でやっとMCをするっていう異業、異業なしとげました。
For this 1st anniversary, I finally did MC work—a monumental, bizarre feat achieved!
ていうことで不慣れです。
So yeah, I'm not used to this.
はい、じゃあ写真撮ってください。イエーイ！はい、はい、いいですか？イエーイ！
Alright, so take a picture. Yay! Alright, alright, ready? Yay!
で、普段ね、自分でも写真撮らないしね、人にもあまり撮られないんでね。貴重な機械！イエーイ！
I don't usually take pictures of myself, and people don't take many of me either. Such a rare machine—I mean occasion! Yay!
ということでね、こ、この、この、こんな感じでハッシュタグなどつけてツイートするといいかもしれないね。
So yeah, tweeting with a hashtag like this might be a good idea.
はい、このあとはですね、ついに、ついにゲストパートです！
Alright, after this is finally, finally the guest part!
今日は、いろんな人に来ていただいておりますよ。ということでね、お楽しみに。
Today, a bunch of people are coming to join us. So look forward to it,
にしていてください。この衣装で歌って踊るよ。見ててね。
please look forward to it. I'll be singing and dancing in this outfit. Watch me!
バイバーイ
Bye-bye!
い〜やい〜やい〜や
I~ya i~ya i~ya
腹据えてりゃ数年ポシャった この怠惰が憎いが
Though I resolved myself, years went to waste, and I hate this laziness,
まだこうしてベッドでまた寝腐っている
yet here I am, rotting away in bed once more.
ここ最近調子は悪いが いや本気はまだまだ
Lately my condition's been poor, but no, my true strength is yet...
そう言ったのはこれで何度目のセリフだろ
How many times have I said that line now?
無造作なヘアー 一重の両目 学歴は中の下で
Messy hair, single-eyelidded eyes, below-average grades,
ご存じモテない 身なりは三流 お涙をどうぞ頂戴
notoriously unpopular, third-rate appearance—give me your pity.
兄弟
Brother!
お涙をどうぞ頂戴 兄弟
Give me your pity, brother!
僕らユートピアじゃないさ
We're not in a utopia,
だから終身刑でいいや
so a life sentence is fine by me.
脳天気したりいいや
Being carefree is fine too,
いやいやいやいや
no, no, no, no!
金環際一生絶賛でいいや
Being praised for life at all costs is fine,
脳天気したい いやいやいやいや
I want to be carefree, no, no, no, no!
最低で結構どうにだっていいや
Being the lowest is fine, whatever happens goes!
夜のセンチメンタル相殺って 希死念慮のロケットを
Offsetting the night's sentimentality, I'm loading the rocket of suicidal thoughts
百四十文字のポエムに放っている
and releasing it into a 140-character poem.
こりゃ相当にbad決まったなら 不夜城に決まりだろ
If this turned out pretty bad, then it's bound for a sleepless city.
ただいつまでこうしてやり過ごすつもりだろ
Just how much longer do I plan on coasting by like this?
負け犬吠える居ないも同然 逃げ足だけが得意の芸
Barking like a loser, practically nonexistent, my only talent is running away.
餌を待つのみ口だけ達者 獲物には即座敗走
Waiting only for handouts, all talk, instantly retreating from prey.
嘘も方便だって言うさ だから同情なんてい〜や
They say a lie can be a convenience too, so I don't need any sympathy.
能天気style い〜やい〜やい〜や
Carefree style, i~ya i~ya i~ya!
嘘も方便だって言うさ
They say a lie is a convenience too,
だからどうしようなんてい〜や
so I don't care what happens anymore!
脳天気したい いやいやいやいや
I want to be carefree, no, no, no, no!
今際一声 本気出したっていいや
Even if I give it my all right now, it's fine,
脳天気したい いやいやいやいや
I want to be carefree, no, no, no, no!
果てまで結構とっくのとうに腐っていいや
Rotting away to the very end long ago is fine!
風邪引いて投げる気が狂った まだスマホをいじった
Catching a cold and losing the will to throw, I was still fiddling with my phone.
ただこうしてベッドで死んだふりをしてる
Yet here I am, playing dead in bed.
くたばったらいっそ楽チンだ ならどうしてそうしない
If I just kicked the bucket it'd be so easy, so why don't I do that?
そりゃ僕がこれっぽっちのヘタレだからだろ
Well, that's because I'm just a tiny coward.
また噂のあいつがバズった まあ正直ジェラった
Once again that rumored person went viral, and honestly, I'm jealous.
ただこうしてベッドで僕は腐っている
Yet here I am, rotting away in bed.
ここ最近調子は悪いが いや本気はまだまだ
Lately my condition's been poor, but no, my true strength is yet...
もうどうにもこうにもなってくれお釈迦様
Buddha, please just let something, anything happen!
脳天気したい いやいやいやいや
I want to be carefree, no, no, no, no!
今際一声 風来坊でいいや
Becoming a vagabond with my dying breath is fine,
脳天気したい いやいやいやいや
I want to be carefree, no, no, no, no!
最低で結構脳無しでいいや
Being the lowest and brainless is fine!
能天気style 明日は頑張っているといいな
Carefree style—I hope I'm trying my best tomorrow.
能天気style だから今日はグダっているい〜や
Carefree style—so today I'm just lazing around!
脳天気したい いやいやいやいや
I want to be carefree, no, no, no, no!
だから今日はダラっていいや
So today, slacking off is totally fine!
一人始めるshowtime
Starting my one-person showtime,
自己満足のpartition
a self-satisfied partition.
誰も踏み込めない 私だけの時間
Time that belongs only to me, where no one can step in.
監督不在の 自己完結なsession
A self-contained session with no director in sight,
誰も邪魔させない 全ては自分次第
letting no one disturb me, everything depends on myself.
使い古したkeyboard 熱めに浸したcoffee
A worn-out keyboard, warmly brewed coffee,
最高速のmy machine 他に何も要らない!
my top-speed machine—I need nothing else!
好きな物を 好きなだけ 集め繋ぎ飾り立てて
Gathering, connecting, and decking out only my favorite things,
この小さな部屋から 今宵 お届けしますone room, all that jazz!
tonight I deliver from this small room: one room, all that jazz!
動き始めるmidnight 事後承諾のpassion
Midnight begins to stir, passion approved after the fact.
その場の アドリブが 思考に先回り 空回り
Ad-libbing on the spot, running ahead of thought and spinning my wheels.
自己解釈のsection のべ幕無し 推敲は後回し
Starting a section of self-interpretation, no curtain call, revision left for later.
使い古したkeyword 語彙の足りないlyric
Worn-out keywords, lyrics lacking in vocabulary,
調子はずれのvocal プライドは要らない!
out-of-tune vocals—I don't need any pride!
駄目な物は 駄目なりに あの手この手で組み上げて
Taking what's no good and putting it together every which way,
一人 始める showtime
A solo showtime begins
自己満足の partition
A partition of self-satisfaction
誰も踏み込めない 私だけの時間
A private time no one else can step into
監督 不在の
With no director present,
自己完結な session
a self-contained session.
誰も邪魔させない 全ては自分次第
Let no one interfere, it's all up to me.
使い古した keyboard
A worn-out keyboard,
熱めに淹れた coffee
hotly brewed coffee,
最高速の my machine
my high-speed machine—
他に何も要らない!
I don't need anything else!
好きな物を好きなだけ 集め繋ぎ飾り立てて
Gathering my favorite things to adorn,
この小さな部屋から 今宵 お届けします
from this small room, I deliver tonight.
好きな物を好きなだけ 集め繋ぎ飾り立てて
Gathering my favorite things to adorn,
この小さな部屋から 今宵 お届けします
from this small room, I deliver tonight...
使い古した keyboard
A worn-out keyboard,
熱めに淹れた coffee
hotly brewed coffee,
最高速の my machine
my high-speed machine—
他に何も要らない!
I don't need anything else!
駄目な物は駄目なりに あの手この手で組み上げて
Making the best of what fails through every trick,
綺麗なリボン飾って
adorning it with a pretty ribbon,
この小さな部屋から 今宵 お届けします
from this small room, I deliver tonight.
駄目な物は駄目なりに あの手この手で組み上げて
Making the best of what fails through every trick,
綺麗なリボン飾って
adorning it with a pretty ribbon,
今宵貴方の方へ 誰より早く お届けします
I deliver to you tonight faster than anyone!
触れてみたい秘密と
With secrets we want to touch
壊してみたい夜の中で
and within the night we want to break,
間違いだらけの遊びをしようよ
let's play a game full of mistakes.
別に意味とか無いけどさ
Not that there's any particular meaning, but
眠い目を擦る
I rub my sleepy eyes.
あれ?待ち合わせは何時?
"Huh? What time is our meetup?"
「君はまだ履き違えている」
"You're still playing the wrong role."
「また間違えている」
"You got it wrong again."
それで?貴方は誰なの
So? Who are you?
こうして居たいが痛いのはお互い様
Wanting to be here hurts us both equally.
目が合う度に名前を呼ばないで
Don't call my name every time our eyes meet.
どうやったって見たいの?
How do you want to see me?
隠さないから
I won't hide it, so
私のフリした私で良ければどうぞ
if you're fine with my pretense, go ahead.
塞ぐ目に墜ちる景色のように
Like the scenery falling upon closed eyes,
霞む私は誰のものでもないの
the hazy me belongs to no one.
buy me
so feeling
からかわないで
Please don't kid around—
私だけに見せて
show it only to me,
歪な夜をどうぞ
here is a twisted night for you.
嘶呼もうほんとうざったいな
Oh, it's really so annoying!
何処かの誰かと
Crossing at a red light with someone somewhere—
赤信号渡る 良いでしょ?
isn't that fine?
ダメダメダメって
Saying "No, no, no,"
分かるでしょ?
you get it, right?
青に染まってたんでしょ?
You were dyed in blue, weren't you?
つまんないな
How boring.
ドクドク流れるテロップ
A telop flowing with a thumping beat,
でも本当うざったいよよよ
Ah, really, it's so annoying!
どっかの誰かと赤の信号渡りよいいでしょ?
Crossing at a red light with someone, isn't that fine?
駄目駄目駄目って分かるでしょ?
Saying "No, no, no," you get it right?
青に染まってたんだってつまんないよ
You were dyed in blue, how boring.
どっかの誰かと赤の信号渡りよいいでしょ?
Crossing at a red light with someone, isn't that fine?
駄目駄目駄目って分かるでしょ?
Saying "No, no, no," you get it right?
青に染まってたんだってつまんないよ
You were dyed in blue, how boring.
独々流れるテロップ
A telop flowing solitarily,
交わす言葉に絡めるシロップ
syrup intertwined with our exchanged words.
早くドキドキさせてよほら
Hurry and make my heart race, hey!
腐敗する誰かと私のエゴ
Someone decaying and my ego,
たまんないわ
it's unbearable.
いつものように
Just like usual,
騙し騙され重なる狂気
madness layering deceit upon deceit,
揺れるように無情に
heartless and swaying,
後はただ墜ちるだけ
after that, all that's left is to fall.
触れてみたい秘密と
With secrets we want to touch
壊してみたい夜の中で
and within the night we want to break,
間違いを繰り返して
repeating mistakes over and over.
触れてみたい秘密を
The secrets we want to touch,
壊して知る夜の味を
knowing the taste of the night by breaking it—
戻れない初めましてをどうぞ
here is a first meeting we can never return to.
塞ぐ目に墜ちる景色のように
Like the scenery falling upon closed eyes,
霞む私は誰のものでもないの
the hazy me belongs to no one.
buy me
so feeling
からかわないで
Please don't kid around—
私だけに見せて
show it only to me,
歪な夜をどうぞ
here is a twisted night for you.
塞ぐ目に墜ちる景色のように
Like the scenery falling upon closed eyes,
霞む私は誰のものでもないの
the hazy me belongs to no one.
buy me
so feeling
からかわないで
Please don't kid around—
私だけに見せて
show it only to me,
秘密の夜をどうぞ
here is a secret night for you.
触れてみたい秘密と
With the secrets we want to try touching
壊してみたい夜の中で
in this night we want to try ruining
間違いだらけの遊びをしようよ
let’s play a mistake-riddled game
赤坂アカ先生、描き下ろしイラストありがとうございます！
Aka Akasaka-sensei, thank you for the new illustration!
え、ちょっと、かっこいい感じの画が入るってことでね、
Um, since it's going to be a cool-looking image,
このあと歌う曲の雰囲気も合わせて描いていただいております。
it was drawn to match the vibe of the song I'll sing next.
勢い大事っすね。
Momentum is important.
人を何人かあやめてきたような雰囲気があります。
It gives off the vibe of someone who's killed a few people.
下手すぎる、感想言うのが下手すぎる。
I'm so bad at giving impressions.
いや、めっちゃ嬉しいです！ありがとうございます！
No, I'm super happy! Thank you so much!
そして、なんと赤坂アカ先生の作品である「推しの子」のアニメ化が決定したそうです！おめでとうございます！
And Aka Akasaka-sensei's work "Oshi no Ko" is getting an anime adaptation! Congratulations!
以前でですね、周央サンゴさんとのコラボ配信で、推しの子いいぞっていうのを、話したことがあるんですけども、
Previously, during a collab stream with Suo Sango, I talked about how great Oshi no Ko is,
今のメンバーがいてね、我々にもううぉーってなってたんでみんな、今のこのの頃のメンバーもううぉーってなってると思います。ありがとうございます！
and we were all going "Whoa!", so I think the members now are all going "Whoa!" too. Thank you!
そして、かぐや様は告らせたいはコミックス最終巻が12月19日、来月発売予定なので、ぜひ貴様らチェックしてくれよな！
And the final volume of Kaguya-sama: Love Is War is out next month on Dec 19th, so you guys check it out!
ばいばい！
Bye-bye!
We have always stood on the borderland.
I'm enjoying the view from here.
Eeny, meeny, miny, moe...
much the same
pike or shield?
We have always stood on the borderland.
負けたくはない でも傷つけたくはない
I don't want to lose, but I don't want to hurt anyone
でも傷つけたくもない
but I don't want to hurt anyone
手に取って確かめてた
I picked it up and checked it
きっと戻れないんだくそっ
I'm sure I can't go back, dammit
Whose side are you on?
(Don't want to know!) 想いは枷
(Don't want to know!) Memories are cangues
(Don't want to know!) 後付けのlove
(Don't want to know!) Retrofit love
(Don't want to know!) 優しさは仇
(Don't want to know!) Kindness is enemy
We have always stood on the borderland.
広げる両手 keep balance
Spread both hands keep balance
より高く飛べる方へ
For those who can fly higher
守りたいよ
I want to protect
僕らの翼のないこの背中に背負った Reality & Dream
I carried it on our wingless back, Reality & Dream
正義だと言う 強さで固めた未来
A future solidified by the strength of justice
嘘だって変わらないさ
Even a lie doesn't change
歯車は回り続けるわ
Gears keep spinning
What color is it?
(You're telling me.) 憎しみは糧
(You're telling me.) Hatred is food
(You're telling me.) 真実は crime
(You're telling me.) The truth is crime
(You're telling me.) 誠実の罠
(You're telling me.) A trap of sincerity
We have always stood on the borderland.
風に吹かれ have a dance
Blow in the wind have a dance
生きているうちに笑え
Laugh while you're alive
この世界の心が 何望んで企ててもそこには
No matter what the heart of this world wants and plots, there is
Reality & Dream
We have always stood on the borderland.
I'm enjoying the view from here.
広げる両手 keep balance
Spread both hands keep balance
より高く飛べる方へ
For those who can fly higher
遠くへ
Fly higher into the distance
気障な穴あけたんだ
You carved a pretentious hole right through it.
支配は始まった
The domination has already begun.
生き様も掛けたの 罰当たりな
Risking your entire way of life is quite blasphemous,
自覚しないはずよ
Though you likely don't even realize it.
抑えきれない 自制不能なパワー
Unstoppable, uncontrollable power!
捕まえてみなよ 影形もないマイハート
Catch if you can, my formless, elusive heart.
I'm so crazy crazy love
半信半疑の素振りは No no
Half-hearted hesitations are a definite no-no.
心に従って
Follow your heart instead.
忠心見せてよ 今こそ
Show me your true loyalty, right here and now!
Baby don't let me down
からめきりみクセになるでしょ？
It's bound to grow on you, right?
手取り足取り魅入られてないのよ
You're still completely enchanted by me!
Yes 感じるでしょ
You can feel it, can't you?
革命的存在を
A revolutionary existence,
いつか爆発したい感情吹き飛ばして
Unleashing suppressed, raw emotions!
儚いはかなき言葉建前並べて
Fleeting words, lined up hypocritically,
何もないことぐらい Baby I know
Are basically meaningless, baby, I know.
臆病者でしょ
Aren't you just a scaredy-cat?
行くこと受け入れたら鮮やかな
If you accept every single thing that comes your way,
フラワー知りながら遅れる笑顔に潜む素顔
A brilliant flower blooms, hidden behind your smiles and tears.
心浸食される前にその身を預けて
Before your heart is eaten away, put your hands together in surrender,
目覚めさせるのよ永遠に
And wake up to eternity!
I never let you down
からめきりみクセになるでしょ？
It's bound to grow on you, right?
手取り足取り魅入られてないのよ Oh no...
You're still completely enchanted by me! Oh no...
Yes 感じるでしょ
You can feel it, can't you?
運命的衝動を
An impulse of destiny,
いつか爆発の内細胞弱らせて
Breaking through the walls of instinct!
時代未来平行並びだ
Visions of the future, lined up in parallel,
意外じゃないアイムアジーニアス前日全能のライクアジーザス
An unexpected omnipotence and omniscience, like Jesus!
待ち焦がれてた道行くのすべて I'm sorry
I'm sorry, I'm so sorry...
誰もが羨む闘技場へと誘じて
Beckoning everyone toward the peak of our battlefield!
Crazy crazy crazy love
天才の常套手段はきっと凡人にはスペシャルね
A genius's standard method is bound to be special to ordinary folks.
誰にも気付かれないけど手に入れるわ
Even if nobody notices, I'll make it mine!
Dark Breath
からめきりみクセになるでしょ？
It's bound to grow on you, right?
手取り足取り魅入られてないのよ
You're still completely enchanted by me!
Yes 感じるでしょ
You can feel it, can't you?
普通じゃない相当いつかプレススタイルかも
An extraordinary style, far from ordinary,
染めさせて
Make it all come together!
あ、待たせた、待たせた、待たせた！
Ah, sorry, sorry, sorry!
え？そんな待たなくていいって？
Ah, you said "Don't wait"?
上手いこと言うね、本当に。
You really know how to talk, honestly...
あ、じゃあ、あの、早速さ、商品の説明に移らせてもらいたくてさ。
Ah, then let's get right into explaining the product!
いやいやいやいや、全然怪しいものとかじゃないから。大丈夫です。
No, no, no, no, it's nothing shady at all, so don't worry.
あ、今日の予定はさ、メールで言った通り、確実に君に幸せをもたらすっていうアイテムなんだけども。
Today's agenda is, as I mentioned in my email, an item guaranteed to bring you happiness!
嘘じゃないって！本当に！
"No way," you say? Seriously!
話聞いてもらえばわかると思うから。ね？
Once you hear me out, you'll understand.
あ、じゃあ、その、1つ目なんだけどさ。
So, for the first item...
はい。これ。
Right. This.
これ、これ、これ。
This, this, this.
Tシャツって感じしてるよね？
It feels like a T-shirt, right?
ただのTシャツじゃないの。
It's not just any T-shirt.
父が違うから。
It's different... or rather,
これ、吉式さんっていう人にね、描き下ろしてもらった。
this was newly drawn for me by someone named Yoshiki-san.
あの、ラプラス・ダークネスさんって知ってる？
Um, do you know Laplus Darknesss?
知る？ あ、知ってる？
You do? Oh, you know her?
あ、いいね。
That's great.
そう、ラプラス・ダークネスさんって人がデザインされたTシャツになってて、
Right, it's a T-shirt designed by Laplus Darknesss,
チャンネル登録者が80万に...
and she's a streamer with over
80万人以上いるっていう、あの、配信者なんだよ。
800,000... 800,000 subscribers, you know.
ただもんじゃないでしょ？
She's no ordinary person, right?
そう。
Right.
そう、このインターネット時代、そう、バズマーケットのイニシアチブを握っているって言っても過言じゃないわけよ。
In this internet age, you could say she holds the initiative in the buzz market.
しかも、有名イラストレーターの吉式さんだからね。
Plus, it's by famous illustrator Yoshiki-san.
これがね、ただのファングッズじゃなくて、普段も着れるデザインになっててね、これがポイントなわけよ。
This isn't just regular fan merch; the design is wearable for everyday life, and that's the key point.
普段着にもよし。
Great for casual wear,
で、イベントの時とかラプラス名言同士のね、この、ファン同士の「愛」にもなれるわけ。この、目と目で分かる。
and for events, it can also become a bond of 'love' between Laplus and her fans... fellow fans. You can tell by locking eyes.
分かる？
You get it?
これ、分かる？これ。
This, you get it? This.
つまりね、ファンのインサイトに寄り添って設計されてるってことなんだよね。
In other words, it's designed closely catering to the fans' insights.
で、なおかつ、こう、身につけることでね、ファン同士の交流も拡大するっていう、シームレスになってるわけ。ね？
And what's more, by wearing it, communication between fans expands seamlessly, right?
いいでしょ？
Isn't it great?
で、これ、2つ目はね、
And, for this, the second one is,
2つ目はね、シルバーリング。
the second one is a silver ring.
これもね、チャンネル登録者80万人以上のラプラス・ダークネスさんが知られたやつですね、これ。
This is also one that Laplus Darknesss, with over 800,000 subscribers, is known for, you know.
いいでしょ？
Nice, right?
なんか、普段使いできるっていうか、日常に溶け込むって感じなわけ。
Well, it feels like something you can use normally, blending into daily life.
普段からラプラス総帥にアグリーしているプラスメイトのマスターアイテムって感じなんだよね。
It feels like a master item for Plasmates who are always in agreement with General Laplus.
ほら、食べるのと一緒。息吸うのと一緒よ。
Look, it's just like eating. It's like breathing.
これ、外見はシンプルなんだけどね、コンペティターとの差別化を図るために、内側にね、あの、ラプラス総帥のね、尻尾のデザインが印刷されてるわけよ。
It looks simple on the outside, but to differentiate from competitors, on the inside, there's a print of General Laplus's tail design.
ただ、分かるものには分かる。伝わるっていうかさ、アザレで仲間意識沸いしちゃうってわけよ。
Only those who know, know. It gets across, or rather, it sparks a sense of camaraderie among us.
あ、で、ここからが本題なんだけど、なんと、この2つさ、セットで買えちゃうのよ。
Oh, and here's the main point: amazingly, you can buy these two as a set!
なんてったって、あの、どっちの商品も、マーケットのニーズが違うから。そうそうそう。
After all, both products have different market needs. That's right, that's right.
で、セットには、複製品入りポストカードがついてきちゃうのよ。
And the set comes with a postcard featuring a duplicated message!
で、しかも、しかもよ、数量限定で、直筆メッセージ&直筆ツメサイン入りポストカードもあるんだって。
And what's more, in limited quantities, there's even a postcard with a handwritten message and autograph!
ちょ、やばいっしょ？ ちょ、き、声、大きくしないでよ。
Wait, isn't that crazy? Shh, k- don't raise your voice!
こんなでっかいビジネスの話ね、まだみんなに知られちゃまずいんだからつって。
Talking about such big business, it's still no good if everyone finds out, you know.
ね？あ、ちょ、ごめんごめん。
Right? Ah, wait, sorry sorry.
あ、お値段。 はあ、図々しいね、君もね。
Ah, the price. Ha, how cheeky of you too.
これ、セットで1万円くらい。1万円しないくらい。そ、そ、そ。
This, as a set, is around 10,000 yen. A bit less than 10,000 yen. R-r-right.
あ、なんていうか、やばいんだって、これ。
How should I put it, it's crazy, this.
この商品が広まれば、幸せになる人たくさん出てくると思うわけ。たくさん。
If this product spreads, I think a lot of people will become happy. A lot.
で、君もその1人。
And you're one of them.
そ。この商品のステークホルダーは僕と君だけじゃないってこと。
Right. The stakeholders of this product aren't just me and you.
夢感じない？
Don't you feel the dream?
ね？あ、そうなんだよね。だから、あ、ごめん。
Right? Ah, that's right. So, ah, sorry.
あ、赤！ ごめん。ちょっと、次のクライアントとかさ、待ってるから。
Ah, red! Sorry. Well, the next client or whatever is waiting, so...
ちょ行かない、行かないんだよね。
I gotta go, gotta go.
ちょっと、ごめんごめんごめん。
Wait, sorry sorry sorry.
あ、貴重な時間ありがとね。ここ会計しとくから。
Ah, thanks for your precious time. I'll take care of the bill here.
あ、じゃあまた！ あ、ありがとうございました！
Ah, see you then! Ah, thank you very much!
LAPLUS DARKNESSS 1周年記念 LIVE
Laplus Darknesss 1st Anniversary LIVE